Exercise 1-50. Contrast of compound nouns. In the following list of words, underline
the element that should be stressed. Repeat after me.
street 7 a main street 8 a hot dog 9 a hot dog 10 a baby blanket 11 a baby's 12 a
baby bird 13 a blackbird 14 a blackbird 15 a greenhouse 16 a greenhouse 17 a green
thumb 18. A parking ticket. 19. A one-way ticket. 20. An unpaid ticket. 21.
Convenience store. 22. Convenience store. 23. To pick up. 24. A pickup truck. 25.
Six years old. 26. A six-year-old. 27. Six and a half. 28. A sugar bowl. 29. A wooden
bowl. 30. A large bowl. 31. A mixing bowl. 32. A top hat. 33. A nice hat. 34. A straw
hat. 35. A chairperson. 36. PhD. 37. IBM. 38. MIT. 39. USA. 40. ASAP. 41. A
doorknob. 42, a glass door, 43, a locked door, 44, ice cream, 45, ice cream, 46,
elementary, 47, a lemon tree 48 Watergate 49 the back gate 50 the final year 51 a
yearbook 52 United States. 53, New York. 54, Long Beach. 55, Central Park. 56, a
raw deal. 57, a deal breaker. 58, the bottom line. 59, a bottom feeder. 60, a
new low. End of CD 2.